<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Charlotte Vrijen</title>
    <link>https://charlottevrijen.com/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://charlottevrijen.com/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Charlotte Vrijen © 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://charlottevrijen.com/media/wordcloud.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://charlottevrijen.com/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intergenerational transmission</title>
      <link>https://charlottevrijen.com/project/intergenerational-transmission/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://charlottevrijen.com/project/intergenerational-transmission/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My postdoc is part of &lt;a href=&#34;https://kretschmertina.wordpress.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;Dr. Tina Kretschmer&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; ERC funded project &lt;a href=&#34;https://kretschmertina.wordpress.com/erc-cape/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;Ghosts from the Past: Consequences of Adolescent Peer Experiences across Contexts and Generations (CAPE)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this project we investigate whether and how peer experiences are transmitted a) to adult friendships and romantic relationships, and b) across generations, i.e., passed on to offspring, to shed light on how the “ghosts from peer past” affect young adults’ relationships and their children’s early social development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our methods include examining longitudinal links between adolescent peer and young adult close relationships and test whether parents’ peer experiences affect offspring’s peer experiences. Psychological functioning, parenting, temperament, genetic, and epigenetic transmission mechanisms are examined separately and in interplay. We utilise data from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.trails.nl/en/home/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;the TRAILS cohort&lt;/a&gt; that has been followed since age 11. To study intergenerational transmission, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.trails.nl/en/hoofdmenu/participants/trails-next/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;TRAILS NEXT&lt;/a&gt; sample of participants with children is substantially extended.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Positive bias and mental health</title>
      <link>https://charlottevrijen.com/project/positive-bias-and-mental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://charlottevrijen.com/project/positive-bias-and-mental-health/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My main line of research concerns positive bias, i.e., the phenomenon that many people see the world more brightly and more positive than it really is, and whether and at what ages individual differences in positive bias are associated with differences in mental and social functioning. In this project I combine longitudinal data collected every 2-3 years with more fine-grained momentary assessments, laboratory tasks, and biomarkers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the key findings of this project is that absence of positive bias during early and mid-adolescence predict onset of depression later in life. My aim for future research is to investigate when and how individual differences in positive bias arise, and what role genetic vulnerabilities and parenting play.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philosophy</title>
      <link>https://charlottevrijen.com/project/philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://charlottevrijen.com/project/philosophy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2007 I completed my first dissertation, entitled &amp;ldquo;The philosophical development of Gilbert Ryle: A study of his published and unpublished writings&amp;quot;This dissertation is the first comprehensive study of the writings, both published and unpublished, of Gilbert Ryle (1900-1976), one of the most well-known and influential philosophers of the twentieth century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to trace the philosophical views of Ryle I not only studied his published writings but also used – for the first time – unpublished sources. This may come as a surprise, for it is commonly believed that Ryle had destroyed early drafts, papers and anything that could be used as a kind of Nachlass by later historians. It was a collection of papers written by Ryle and posthumously edited by René Meyer (1993) that first made it clear to me that at least some material had escaped Ryle’s destructive hand. Soon after I had started my PhD-work in 2001, I found out that there does exist a sort of ‘Ryle Collection’ at Linacre College, virtually unknown to the scholarly world, which consists of a substantial part of what was once his own philosophical library and several unpublished documents. I also found several minor collections of Ryle material – letters, notes, typescripts of conversations, correspondences and papers – at various other places in Oxford, e.g. the New Bodleian, the Philosophy Library and Nuffield College. The correspondences include an important exchange between Ryle and Collingwood.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
